Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode.
Subtitles will likely not function properly.
Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv:
https://mpv.io
Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode.
Subtitles will likely not function properly.
Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv:
https://mpv.io
Ace! Luffy!
We gotta set out to sea someday!
Let's get out of this country and live freely!
Starting today...
we're brothers!
– Yeah!
How long are you gonna keep moping?
All the treasure we hid
in the midway forest is gone.
But that pile of loot doesn't matter anymore.
That was the pirate fund
Sabo and I were gonna use...
But in the end, Sabo didn't need it.
So I'll just let it go, too.
There's no point in gathering
treasure you can't even protect.
A-Ace...
I...
I wanna get stronger!
And stronger...
and stronger...!
Stronger and stronger!
Lots stronger!
Stronger!
Lots and lots stronger!
Stronger and stronger!
So much stronger!
And stronger and stronger!
And even stronger than that!
And then, I'll be able to protect anything.
I won't have to lose anyone ever again!
So please...
Ace, please don't die!
Don't be ridiculous!
Worry about yourself first!
You're way weaker than me!
Listen up, and remember this, Luffy!
I'm not gonna die!
Uh-huh.
Sabo made that request, too.
I promise. There's no way I'll die!
How could I die and leave my
wimpy little brother behind?
Uh-huh... Uh-huh!
I'm not that smart so I don't know
what even killed Sabo.
But... it must've been
the opposite of freedom.
Sabo died without tasting freedom.
But we shared the same cup of sake
with Sabo, and we're still alive!
So, listen up, Luffy.
We have to live our lives without regrets!
Uh-huh.
Noble-born boys...
become true noblemen
on their eighteenth birthday.
That's why I need to leave this country
by the time I turn seventeen!
Someday, we'll head out to sea...
and live however we want!
We'll be more free than anyone!
Uh-huh!
I'm sure we'll make lots
of enemies because of that.
Even Grandpa will be against us.
We'll be risking our lives.
We set sail at seventeen!
And then...
we will become pirates!
Let us turn back the clock once more...
to the night when the Celestial Dragon's
ship docked in Goa Kingdom.
In a certain region of the East Blue,
in a small seaside village...
Did you see the guy with
the huge face this afternoon?!
Yeah! I've never seen anything like it!
Look! His ship is huge too!
Five hundred and eighty...
Five hundred and eighty-one...
Five hundred and eighty-two...
Five hundred and eighty-three...
Five hundred and eighty-four...
You are late, Dragon!
How long did you plan to make us vayyt?!
Sorry.
Vhaat did you...?!
This is awful!
Quickly! Get a doctor! It's an emergency!
Roger!
But really! Vherre have you been?!
I was watching the world noble's
arrival ceremony.
You vennt on your own viithout telling me?!
If you were there, too, we would've
stuck out like sore thumbs.
You mean... this...?!
We must strive to grow
ever stronger, and with haste!
How are our provisions?
There was a village dojo that offered us food.
Then we set sail!
We will return to Baltigo!
Some months later, the World Government having
concluded their inspection of the Kingdom of Goa...
They've brought more trash!
The people have settled
into their old routines...
and the trash mountain has accumulated anew.
Here I come, Ace!
Gum-Gum...
Pistol!
What the hell was that? You call this a fight?
You might pack a punch,
but what's the use if you miss every time?
I told you, rubber really isn't suited for battle.
Shut up! Don't say that!
What?! I'm telling the truth!
Sure, attacks bounce off you,
but you sink like a rock now!
Stop making fun of the Gum-Gum Fruit!
I'll make you cry someday!
I'm coming up with moves
even better than the pistol!
Luffy, great work!
Your arm stretched a lot farther
than it did yesterday!
Sabo! You're too soft on Luffy!
I knew I was stronger than yesterday!
– Right, Sabo?!
Sabo was such a nice older brother...
Say what?! You wish I'd died instead?!
Ow. Huh?
I've founded my own country.
A country?
What's this?
Me too!
What is it this time?!
I'm gonna learn to survive on my own.
You guys can be Dadan's country.
I'll borrow the bath sometimes.
Ace! Help me out! It's a bear!
You said you'd survive on your own, right?!
Dammit!
Luffy!
Hey! Dadan's country! Anyone there?!
Luffy got hurt! He needs first aid!
Magra! Please, help Luffy!
Take it easy! Hurry! Bring him in!
Now, take it easy. This is no joke.
If his wounds were any deeper,
it could've been fatal!
You used to take on those
wild beasts as a trio, right?
It's my fault!
I should've learned by now that fighting
on your own doesn't prove that you're strong!
I'm no good!
No good at all!
Ace...
I'm so sorry, Luffy!
I'm sorry!
Hey, you guys!
Makino came all the way
out here to bring us some drinks!
You want to learn how to thank someone?
Uh-huh.
What's gotten into you?
Seeing as I'm Luffy's big brother and all,
I'd like to meet this Captain Red Hair someday
and properly thank him for everything he did for Luffy.
Say something, will you?!
I'm sorry.
Okay then, I'll teach you.
So, first of all...
It's a dine and dash!
Stop!
Oh, we're forgetting something important!
Oh, right...!
– Thanks for the food!
Shut up, you damn kids! Just pay the bill!
I'm gonna win today!
– Alright!
Tonight, we're having bear stew!
Take care, Ace!
Will do! See you later, Luffy!
I'm heading out now!
Yeah! And I'll be a lot stronger
when I set out in three years!
Give it your all, Ace!
Take care of yourself!
Try not to catch a cold!
Just you wait! I'll make
a name for myself real soon!
Ace, the son of the Pirate King,
grew up in complete secrecy...
and quiety departed from
the shore near Mt. Colubo.
There he goes!
Honestly. How is Garp going to take this?
You're gonna raise him, Dadan!
No, wait! Whose kid is that?!
Boss...
Ace just left.
Did he, now?
But I'll be the one Garp chews out...
What a hopeless little shit.
Oh, and Ace left a message for you!
What?! He's finally gone
and he's still complaining?!
He said, "Thank you for everything."
Give me a break! That idiot!
What? Boss, are you crying?
I'm not crying, you idiot!
Only three more years for me!
Gum-Gum...
Pistol!
Damn... Just a little off...
That was close, Luffy!
Try lowering your center of gravity.
Gum-Gum...
Pistol!
I wanna get stronger!
And stronger!
Luffy!
Look at the newspaper!
What's up?
Just look!
So cool! Ace made a name for himself!
It's a picture of his pirate ship and crew!
Amazing! Ace is amazing!
But I'm not gonna lose to him!
Hey, come on!
I'm leaving now. You're not gonna see me off?
Hey!
Shut up...!
The mayor and Makino are okay with us,
but we'd send the rest of Windmill Village
into a panic if we came down the mountain!
But...
Just get going already!
Oh, okay. Well then, guys...
Thanks for everything!
Oh, don't embarrass us.
No need for thanks.
Take it easy and take care.
Yep! Sure thing!
Oh, right!
Dadan, I hate mountain bandits...
Shut up, you little turd!
...but I like you guys!
Don't say dumb stuff like that!
Just get lost already, dammit!
Sheesh! Every last one of you...!
What, are you crying?
No! I'm absolutely not!
Windmill Village, at the outskirts of
the Kingdom of Goa on Dawn Island...
Hey! You're going out to sea, so just
take my old fishing boat, Luffy!
You'll sink right away in that thing!
A rowboat? C'mon!
Seriously, I'm fine with this!
It's the start of my journey!
Sabo!
Watch over me! I'm gonna set out to sea now!
Sabo was first. Ace was second.
I'm third, but I won't lose to them!
Wait for me, Ace!
I'll catch up to you soon enough!
What're you doing, Luffy,
shouting to yourself like that?
Is it some sort of good luck charm?
It's not a charm. It's a challenge!
Who's Ace?
Not a clue.
Alright, I'm outta here!
Well, Mayor, he's finally off.
I'm gonna miss him.
He's disgracing our village
by becoming a pirate!
What a nice day to set sail!
Th-That's...!
If it isn't the Lord of the Coast.
You don't know who you're messing with.
Check out this technique
ten years in the making!
Gum-Gum...
Pistol!
That'll teach you! Damn fish!
Incredible! He beat the
Lord of the Coast with one punch!
He's sure grown strong.
First, I've gotta gather a crew.
Ten people oughta do it!
I'll also need a Jolly Roger!
Alright! Let's go!
I'm gonna be...
King of the Pirates!
We return to the present.
His brother Ace is dead,
and Luffy mourns his loss.
Luffy...
Me, the King of the Pirates?!
I'm...
so weak!
It's Garp!
Garp's returned on his battleship!
On business?!
Garp, we read all about the war!
A resounding Marine victory, right?!
Yeah, and everyone here is safe?
Is Luffy okay?!
With Whitebeard dead, what'll happen
to the world?! Tell us, Garp!
These past few days, we've seen
a lot of pirate ships on the open sea.
The thought of being raided
keeps us up at night!
Rest easy! I just sank
three of 'em on the way here.
Really? That's good to hear!
Amateurs like them don't know
their way around a fight!
Although, Whitebeard was
a stabilizing factor...
With him gone, every sea in the world
will become turbulent.
Don't let your guard down just because
you live in a remote part of the East Blue.
Hey!
– Yes, sir!
"Security, courtesy of Marine HQ's
Vice Admiral Garp," huh?
That's so reassuring!
There's nothing to be afraid of now!
Garp, we have another problem.
Bandits came down out of the
mountains and took over Makino's bar!
Bandits?
Stop! Don't!
Hey, Garp!
Oh, that's her!
You've got some nerve
showing your face here again!
Garp!
B-Boss!
Vice Admiral Garp!
Stand down! I know her.
You...
You were right there on the battlefield!
They were right in front of you!
So, what the hell were you doing?!
What the hell were you doing?!
Why?! Why?! Why?!
Why?! Why?!
Why did you just stand there and let Ace die?!
Is duty more important than your family?!
Right, Garp?! And they
call you the Hero of the Marines!
Shrivel up and die, you geezer!
Take it easy, boss! That's too far!
– Boss...
Garp, cat got your tongue?!
You could have saved him!
Why didn't you do something?!
Stand up! Get on your feet!
You inhuman filth!
That's enough, Dadan!
Makino...
They may have been within arm's reach,
but there was nothing he could do!
The one hurting most here is Garp!
Y-You're wrong...
You're wrong...
You're wrong!
Luffy's the one who's hurting most!
Now, try to imagine that he's
right here in front of you.
I'm Ace! Who the hell are you?
Bzzt! That's a no-go.
"Who the hell" is too rude.
Is it, "Oh, it's you?!"
Give me your name.
Bzzt!
And just who are you?
Is it, "Who's that?"
Bzzt! Bzzt!
All wrong. Are you even trying?
It's because you keep
distracting me with dumb stuff!
Quit it!
Hey, Ace!
Yesterday, I found the nest of a giant snake,
and it was filled with humongous eggs!
Let's go get them!
Huh? Humongous eggs?
No, not right now!
I'm studying how to greet people!
It'll be real bad if that giant snake
catches me when I go by myself!
But I'll be fine if you're with me. C'mon!
Shut up!
You have to know how much
he looked up to his brother!
Makino!
Garp...
What happened with Luffy?
The newspapers say he's gone missing.
Mayor...
He escaped in a submarine.
Marines pursued him with everything they had
and conducted a thorough search.
But no shipwreck was found.
At least for now... he's alive!
Thank goodness!
So, how's Marine Vice Admiral Garp
connected to this mountain bandit?
Who knows?
Luffy might be an idiot,
but no matter what kind of pirate
he becomes, I will always stand beside him.
When I think about how he must be feeling,
it's like my heart is getting torn in half.
Luffy!
Don't you dare let this stop you!
Now, we take a look far away...
to somewhere in the second half
of the Grand Line, the New World.
Red Hair...
How can I thank you for this?
Don't be ridiculous.
He may have been my enemy,
but Whitebeard was a man worthy of respect.
Even Sengoku thought so.
Well, it's time we parted ways.
Yeah. Thanks.
Luffy, this must be difficult for you.
Word of Ace's final moments
took me by surprise.
Take back what you just said!
Don't you dare mock the man who saved me!
This era will be named after Whitebeard!
His actions were just like...
Captain Roger's.
I sometimes wished the captain would retreat.
I wished he would cry.
Listen to me, Luffy.
When you experience both victory and defeat,
and when you flee from battle and shed tears,
that is when you grow into a man.
It's okay to cry.
Overcome this!
Dammit! I'm so weak! I can't protect anyone!
Luffy.
Go away!
Leave me alone!
I can't do that! I can't stand
to let you hurt yourself further!
It's my body! I'll decide what I do with it!
Then by the same token,
Ace's body was also his own...
His death was his decision!
Just shut the hell up!
One more word, and I'll kick your ass!
You're welcome to try
if it'll make you feel better!
I, too, am injured... but I won't
lose to you! Not as you currently are!
Gum-Gum...
Pistol!
Jinbe...
While I was out chasing Teach...
I met my little brother for the first time
in three years in the Kingdom of Alabasta.
As soon as I saw him, I felt relieved.
Do you know why?
Ow! That hurts!
I said that hurts, you punk!
Did you lose sight of everything?!
You believed that you
could overcome anything!
And you never doubted your strength!
But a horde of enemies ruthlessly shattered your
beliefs and rendered you unable to do a thing...
And your brother was your
guiding light on this sea!
You've lost so much...
The world itself has become your
greatest obstacle yet, blocking your vision!
You can no longer see the path forward!
Dark clouds of regret and guilt consume you!
Your pain overwhelms you, Luffy,
but put an end those feelings!
Stop dwelling on what you've lost!
What's gone is gone!
What is it that you still have?!
Luffy, don't mess around up here!
My regimen needs focus!
Luffy, hurry and get everyone into position!
There's a storm ahead!
Just you wait and see, Luffy!
I'm gonna catch a big one soon!
Luffy, it's almost done. Be patient and wait!
Luffy, no matter the injury,
you're in good hands!
I'll always fix you up, good as new!
Oh, Luffy.
If you're interested, I can
teach you about archeology.
Hey, Luffy! The cola engine
is purring like a kitten today!
You can leave everything
about the Sunny to me!
Good morning, Luffy! Rise and shine!
Well then, let's get started
with a morning ditty!
Luffy.
Luffy!
– Luffy!
My crew...
I still have my crew!
Zoro! Nami! Usopp!
Sanji! Chopper! Robin!
Franky! Brook!
I still have my friends!
I see.
We promised to meet up somewhere.
Guys, meet back at the Sunny in three days!
– Okay!
I gotta get there...
even though I'm running late.
I'm sure they're all waiting for me!
What I saw there... Jinbe...
An older brother can't help worrying...
about their kid brother.
I'm sure he's been a handful...
Take care of him for me.
I saw that Luffy's no longer that kid
who couldn't help but follow me everywhere.
You see now...
he has a crew he can rely on.
No matter what happens, he'll be just fine.
I was so relieved.
I... wanna see them.
I really wanna see them!
7 Years Later
Ace, 17 Years Old
Luffy, 14 Years Old
Several Months Later
m 399 342 l 1519 353 1560 749 381 713
3 Years Later
Luffy, 17 Years Old
m 476 99 l 1437 111 1816 956 98 945
Windmill Village, Kingdom of Goa, East Blue
Isle of Women, Calm Belt