Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode.
Subtitles will likely not function properly.
Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv:
https://mpv.io
Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode.
Subtitles will likely not function properly.
Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv:
https://mpv.io
Whitebeard's era is over.
Burning ambition spurs pirates
the world over into action.
And then there's Trafalgar Law...
What? We're still not going?
Let's just go to the New World already!
I told you, we're waiting for the right time.
Don't rush things.
The great treasure, One Piece, isn't going anywhere.
But you know, Blackbeard and his group
are causing a stir in the New World!
Rumor has it that they've
already crushed one pirate crew!
These 100-million-bounty rookies are streaming
into the New World to snag a spot as an Emperor!
If we keep hanging back here,
we're gonna fall behind, Captain!
It's better for us if they're
trying to destroy one another.
We won't get involved in those petty fights.
Quit whining and just follow my orders.
When the time is right,
we'll rise to the top.
Captain!
We'll follow you anywhere!
Aye aye, Captain!
Kaido, one of the Four Emperors,
highly favors this island base.
And I'm in charge of security here.
And? What do you want me to do?
I'm not telling you to do anything.
It's just a warning.
You're better off not angering Kaido, rookie.
In other words, if I take your head,
then Kaido will come for mine?
Now he gets it! If so, then you can–
That simplifies the matter!
An ancient zoan type, huh? Now, that's rare!
Scratch...
Boom!
\h\h\hThere're quite a few left...!
\h\h\hWe really stepped in it...
Ouch...
Don't worry, guys! We've got
Captain Apoo on our side!
Listen up, men!
– Aye!
Make a run for it!
– What?!
There's no winning against
a herd of those wild boars!
Captain! We're headed straight for a cliff!
It's our best bet for escape!
Oh no! We're done for!
Don't give up!
But the ocean's right beneath that cliff!
Who cares?! Jump!
– What?!
What the...?!
Captain! I don't know if you noticed,
but we're running on air!
The boars are following us into the air too!
I can see that!
What the hell is with this island?!
It's so hot...
My legs can't take it anymore.
There's no strength in my body either...
Ouch. A fish just bit me.
Quit your bellyaching, Wolf!
Our raft almost broke because of you.
That's why we're in this situation.
Trying to sail the seas of the New World
on that raft was an absurd idea anyway.
We should've stolen a warship back at Marineford!
We had grown attached to that raft, though.
You guys don't prepare for anything.
Put me in command!
I'll take over as captain for you, Teach.
Don't make me kill you.
We're the Blackbeard Pirates.
Heaven already knows the fate of all.
We're running low on booze.
Can't we go to an island with a town?
I agree.
But forget the ship; I need some nicer clothes.
I'm so sick of these prison clothes.
I'll go take a look.
They're taking too long.
No argument here. But these guys
sure look to be going numb.
Ain't that right...
Jewelry Bonney?
Captain Bonney...
I'm impressed that a young lady like yourself
managed to get a bounty of over 100 million!
The New World is best left to the strong.
You did well making it
this far from the South Blue,
but this is the last stop on your voyage.
I don't need a weakling like you on my crew.
However, if you become my woman,
I'll gladly take you along.
Come see the waters ahead. Huh?
Screw you, you bearded pig!
Seems you've been rejected.
Forget it! You're one crude bitch!
A woman should be classy, after all!
I've already got all the ruffians
I need on my crew!
Yeah, you tell her!
We'll stick to the plan where
we hand you off to the Marines
in exchange for a proper warship!
Captain.
Huh?
I can see the Marines.
They've got the warship
they promised us, right?!
There's indeed a ship,
but I doubt it's intended for us.
Huh? How can you tell?
Akainu is on board.
Damn! This just got too rich for me!
Let's get the hell outta here!
A complete failure!
Where's Blackbeard?
He's gone!
When I heard you'd fled from the government,
my blood ran cold.
But it's all over now.
You bastards are gonna pay!
He vanished?!
Yup, that's the honest truth.
Whose idea was this?! Sengoku's?!
No... Even higher than that.
And I'm not talking in metaphors.
Literally, he was gone like "poof"!
It surprised me. I had no idea that
the Shadow-Shadow Fruit could do that.
This is no laughing matter!
It's fine. He was on the verge of death.
There's nothing he can do now.
Unless he somehow turned himself
into a zombie, you know?
That sure would suit him, after all.
You're too nonchalant
about your sloppy work!
Don't get so cocky with me!
When, exactly, did you become my boss?!
No matter how far up the government
ladder you've climbed, I'm a pirate.
So I don't care!
The moment I lose interest in our little deal,
I'll just drop out of the Seven Warlords!
Don't ever forget that.
M-Mister Tanuki!
We tell you come back anytime,
but this too soon, right?
No, you've got the wrong man!
I may look like him, but I'm
actually his friend, Chopper Mask!
You trying too hard, Mister Tanuki.
You use disguise to hide being
embarrassed when coming back so soon?
That's not it at all! I'm–
Mister Tanuki okay?
All being very mean.
In situation like this, must play along.
Fine, you win!
Your kindness got to me!
Oh, Mister Tanuki!
That tickles, you jerk!
Truth be told, something came up.
Mind if I stay a bit longer?
No worry! You very welcome here.
There are so many plants growing
on that tree that I've never seen before.
Please let me study them!
In that case, we have perfect place.
Also, I need to become
stronger and more capable.
No time to waste.
Oh, Mister Tanuki? Back already?
This great!
Everyone, I'll be staying on this island
for a while, so let's get along!
Right, this is place.
What is this?
This be...
village library.
Use for research.
Look at all the books!
There're so many,
all the way from front to back!
Incredible!
They're all books about the plants I want
to research and the medicines I want to make!
There's no end to them!
On island, many plants make strong medicine.
Our technology make medicine, but birds
always keep ingredients away from people.
Was big problem for all.
I misjudged these islanders
due to their appearance,
but now that I think about it,
their weapons are really advanced.
They all resembled primitive savages,
but the science here is actually far along!
There's so much to learn here!
Mister Tanuki!
Maybe think you say all in head,
but every word Mister Tanuki say out loud.
And very rude too!
This country... I wonder how much
I can do while I'm here!
It's a yeti!
Shoot it dead!
Don't let it get away!
Take it down!
Pirates are incredible!
There are countless people like that out at sea!
Chopper, go out to sea some day.
If you do, you'll realize just how
small your own problems are.
Compared to the rest of the world,
your home island is this small!
Really?
No, it's smaller! Like this! It's true!
I'm not even a human!
I'm a monster!
I can't join your crew!
So...!
So I just came to say thank you...
I really appreciate you guys.
Thank you for asking me to join you.
I'll stay here, but...
one day, if you feel like it, stop by agai–
Shut up!
Let's go!
Ever since Luffy brought me out to sea,
it's been a struggle just to keep up.
How can I contribute more, Luffy?
I never want to experience
anything like that again.
But...
back then...
Luffy... was probably
in more pain than any of us!
Because you made me
one of your crewmates...
I've been just fine, not caring
what others thought about me.
If it means I can be of any help to you...
then I'll even become a real monster!
Chopper!
Luffy!
I...
will definitely...
become stronger!
The Kamabakka Queendom
on the Grand Line....
Vhaat exactly did you see in that article?
I read you loud and clear...
You calmed down so suddenly...
That article contained a message from Luffy
that only his crewmates would understand.
But you don't believe I'm his crewmate,
so I'm not telling you what I saw, dumbass!
Annoying punk!
Hey, who made this food?
Oh? That is a discerning
palate you have there.
Not only does it taste sublime, it's as if...
my body is getting rejuvenated.
Indeed. This is aggression cuisine!
Many chefs on this island
can make this dish!
Yes!
Yes!            Yes!
– Yes!
Behold! The candies of this island
have beautiful yet strong physiques!
Kind hearts, too.
My candies developed this vayy
by eating aggression cuisine!
Your diet decides your condition,
your physique,
and your personality!
You are vhaat you eat!
If 100 percent of the human population
drank milk every day...
crime across the voorld vould disappear, no?!
Hm?
You see...
no aggression, no progression!
Using food to build one's physique...
I never thought about it that way.
So every day I cook for them
could help their development?
And then...
I could make Nami and Robin's
bodies even sexier?!
Vhaat should I do viith you?!
What should I do?!
I'm burning with passion!
Please teach me aggression cuisine!
The answer is no!
Ouch...
The Kamabakka Queendom's 99 Vital Recipes
have been passed down as part of
the Newkama Kenpo secret arts:
Bride Training!
It vill be a cold day in hell...
before I let a total stranger
like you learn them!
That is, unless you open
your heart to your femininity!
Study Newkama kenpo!
I refuse!
I was not born to merely befriend the ladies.
I am a man who was born...
to give them my love!
Heehaw!
– Yahoo!
– Yay!
– Sanji!
Vhaat a compelling speech! I like you!
So I vill give you a chance!
A chance?
On this island resides ninety-nine
Newkama Kenpo grandmasters,
and I vill hand out one recipe to each of them.
If you are indeed a pirate,
then steal every one of those recipes!
However! It vill be hell for you, day and night,
as every Newkama here attempts
to put this Ssveets dress on you!
I vaant to see if you maintain
your manly composure!
Sanji-kins!
We won't let you sleep!
The Sweets dress.
I will make you remember
the joy of wearing a skirt!
Sanji!
It's nice to be girly!
You...
versus the Newkama Kenpo head temple!
Come out on top,
and I vill even give you a ship!
Vhaatever you vaant is yours!
Now, decide!
Hey you, cook!
Join my crew!
Be the cook on my pirate ship!
Is your lack of an answer
an indication that you give up?
Because when you lose–
When I win...
Wha...?
When I beat all of them...
I bet I'll be much stronger than I am now.
Even if you pierce his body
with hundreds of weapons,
nobody stands a chance against
a spear of blind determination.
Hey, Luffy...
don't lose.
I am hoping to head out someday...
to the Grand Line.
Then let's go now!
It's not the right time yet.
Hey...
have you heard of the All Blue?!
Nope.
You've seriously never heard of it?!
That sea itself is a miracle!
We both have foolish dreams.
To achieve my goal—to find the All Blue...
Sanji?
Yeah. I'll come along on your journey
to become King of the Pirates!
Huh?
I'll be the cook for your ship.
Luffy, the next time we meet...
I will...
support you as the world's greatest cook
so that you can become King of the Pirates.
I will...
live through...
this hell!
I accept...
your challenge!
That is great!
No holding back, dearies!
Here I come!
I will definitely...
win!
On the small sky island, Weatheria...
The research she stole...
...the weather ball...
...and her hostage, Mr. Haredas!
We won't forgive you just because
you returned everything!
I'm sorry. I truly regret my actions.
No, we can't trust her!
Strip her of all that she has and banish her!
Please don't!
Well then, to prove my remorse,
I will throw myself into the sea.
– What?!
Please forgive me in my next life!
Farewell!
We made her cry!
Don't jump the gun!
You're too young to just up
and throw your life away!
Goodbye...
– We're sorry!
Sounds good. I forgive you.
Well, I'll be staying here awhile
to study up on your weather science.
Oh, my name is Nami.
Miss Nami if you please.
Also, I'll need a house of my own.
Privacy is important, you know.
I require a soft, fluffy bed,
a hot tub, and a walk-in closet.
I'm counting on you, sky geezers.
So, let's do our best!
Yeah!
Mr. Haredas, say something already!
Good grief...
Weatheria drifts around the world
wherever the wind may take it.
We sometimes visit the surface
to gather goods and information,
and then we continue on our way.
Information?
Well, records mostly.
Records regarding the Grand Line's
unbelievable weather phenomena,
many of which are still–
What's this?!
Are you listening?
Huh?! You've gotta be kidding me!
Lightning strikes like rain?!
Indeed. It literally rains lightning.
The lightning strikes the island like it's raining.
It happens on an island in the New World.
If you plan to cross that sea,
remember that it defies
common sense like no sea before it.
Please... teach me, Mr. Haredas.
The New World's weather...
Teach me all about it!
You seem desperate.
Well, of course I am! My actions
determine the lives of my crewmates!
I'm their navigator!
Out at sea, I have the
biggest responsibility of all!
It's my job to take the captain
wherever it is he wishes to go!
Luffy says he wants to
become King of the Pirates,
so I can't take my job as a navigator lightly!
It must make your captain very happy
to have such a thoughtful crew member.
I don't have a choice.
You don't?
That's right. I mean, he talks a big game,
but he's utterly clueless about the ocean.
He's always doing the craziest things.
If I left him alone...
Luffy...
Help me...
Of course I will!
He'd get himself killed without me.
He's a high-maintenance idiot!
He sounds like one troublesome captain!
He is. That's why I'm gonna help him.
This time, I will!
Hey, tell me about the weather balls.
You ask like it's no big deal! This is
Weatheria's greatest invention, after all!
In the wrong hands, they could
throw the entire world into disarray!
So it has combat potential?
Hey now, don't go saying
such dangerous things!
Stop grinning!
Nami!
You're one of us!
This is the Kingdom of Armsolong
on Sword Mountain Island in the Grand Line.
Come one! Come all!
This creature has the
appearance of a real skeleton!
What's more, his arms only have a single joint!
Have you ever seen
a rarer creature than this?!
Hey! Don't pull a fast one, you con artists!
What? Does he not fascinate you?
That thing hasn't moved one bit!
It's just a big doll, isn't it?!
Luffy has made his decision.
And so, I should make one too.
Hey, skeleton! Don't jerk us around!
I cannot just sit here!
Oh, so you understand? That's right, move!
This is a show, after all!
What can I do to help?
Just moving around would be
plenty helpful! So move already!
What's going on here?!
When you saw me for the first time,
you weren't the least bit scared,
and you even asked me to join your crew.
Anyway... Hey, you!
Join my crew!
Yes. That sounds lovely.
– What?!
Fifty long years...
Could you imagine my joy, especially
after drifting on that dark sea for so long?
A certain man stole my shadow.
Don't act like we're strangers!
If you need your shadow,
I'll get it back for you!
Do you realize how brilliantly
you were shining to me?
Fifty years of hoping for a miracle,
and that moment fulfilled my wish.
Give me back my money!
Yeah!
Damn! I thought he'd be our
meal ticket, but it looks hopeless.
If he won't comply, we'll just have to–
What the...?!
– Huh?!
– Oh...?
– Huh...?
Forty degrees!
– What?!
Ah! That's difficult!
He's really talking and moving!
How creepy!
What is that thing?!
If I try going below 45 degrees,
I end up slipping.
However, once I can master this...
I may be of more use to Luffy.
Or perhaps I should find another way...
He's got a guitar!
What's he about to do?
What is it this time?!
Anything extra is too much!
This is just a freak show!
"Freak show" works for me!
Call it whatever you wish.
"Loneliness" no longer exists in my vocabulary!
Ladies and gentlemen!
I'm sure you're all bored just staring at me.
What's this rhythm?
It speaks to my soul!
Please listen to my new single,
"Bone to Be Wild"!
Meanwhile, just below
the East Blue's colossal bridge...
Why the sudden change of heart?
You're coming with us to Baltigo?
If so, we are extremely grateful.
Dragon has always wanted to meet you.
I didn't know you were such charitable people.
I wish you would have
sought me out much sooner.
W-We're sorry! We hadn't heard
about your team-up with Crocodile.
I'm joking. Just a bit of fun, but I apologize.
I'm glad things turned out the way they did.
Set sail! Set sail for Baltigo!
Seventy-nine million belly?!
A bounty that high for an eight-year-old girl?!
They say she's a survivor of those Ohara devils
who were plotting the world's destruction.
Ohara?
I don't know how, but they say
that she sank six Marine battleships.
That explains the high bounty.
She's a devil's spawn
who shouldn't be left alive!
Alright! Just wait right there!
Why are you trying to save me?!
When did I ever ask you to do this?!
I just... want to die!
No way!
Are you all insane?!
You're all as good as dead after
making the world your enemy!
Bring it on!
Robin, please come inside.
It's cold out here.
I'll be fine out here.
I'm a pirate. You are revolutionaries.
I can't trust you so easily.
I won't enter a cabin
where there's no escape route.
But that's...! We have
no intention of harming you!
Just let me stay. Back when I was
on my own, this was how I lived.
My apologies! Very well.
Hey! Bring out as many
warm blankets as you can!
And something hot to drink and eat, too!
B-But we set that all up inside...
Hop to it! A wind screen and sofa too!
Yes, sir!
Luffy, if I go to your father and let the
world's tides carry me where they will,
I wonder if I can become a little stronger?
Wanting to become stronger
for the sake of someone else...
I'd never considered it before.
We now return to Mech Island
on the Grand Line...
Futureland, Baldimore...
We've investigated the destruction
of Doctor Vegapunk's laboratory...
but we still haven't found the culprit.
Hey! Hurry up!
It wouldn't be an exaggeration to call
this the greatest loss of the century.
Do you know anything about it?
I heard that an intruder
resembling a gorilla entered the lab.
This is a real head-scratcher.
It's impossible to reach this island
without an icebreaker ship.
But no one seems to have seen it.
They say that the intruder was
Cyborg Franky of the Straw Hat Pirates,
but he was spotted less than
a month ago on Sabaody Archipelago.
We have no idea what route or means
he used to get to Baldimore.
Captain Gorilla! The search party is
departing for the snow mountains!
Very well! I shall accompany them!
Th-This is...!
The explosion exposed a hidden entrance.
I can hardly believe it. We had no idea...
that there was a second laboratory in here.
This seems to be where he created
all those cyborg animal guards.
Hey, don't break anything!
You're one to talk, old guy!
The blown-up lab had some radical inventions
that would have changed how people live,
but I was more interested
in the weaponry I found here.
This is amazing!
It's everything from warships
to human genetics!
What's going on inside this guy's head?
Okay, I've made up my mind!
I'm gonna live here!
Wha...?! Live here?!
Yeah!
I'll come down the mountain
sometimes for more cola,
so don't forget to keep
your house stocked, you hear?!
Don't sweat it!
As long as you don't rat me out,
I'll live here and keep to myself.
Quit screamin'! It's just my face!
Don't look at us!
Your face is too scary!
How's this? A tiger-skin rug.
– Much better.
Frah... Frah... Frah-nky!
I'm freezing. Especially my legs.
Why won't you put on pants?
Would you please sail
on the ship that I've built?
Luffy... you helped me carry out my dream.
Franky!
Thanks for the ship!
It really is the best! We'll take good care of it!
If you want your bikini back,
you'll just have to join our crew!
You took me along for the ride
in this wild, wide world.
Passing through sea after sea,
overcoming countless battles and troubles.
And once we've sailed to the end of the sea,
then we can truly say
she was the ship of dreams.
Hey, Luffy.
The Sunny still hasn't shown her full potential!
And the captain to make
the Sunny my dream ship...?
That's you.
I'll learn the technologies necessary to get
the better of tough adventures to come...
tougher than any so far.
So, Luffy...!
Hey. The tiger's on fire.
Ow, ow, ow, ow...!
What's that?!
A monster?! Be careful!
So, Luffy, let's overcome the rough
waves of the New World together!
This incident in the Grand Line
is forever referred to as:
"The Legend of the Burning Spirit Beast of Baldimore."
Meanwhile...
on the Bowin Archipelago in the Grand Line...
What is it now'n, Usopp'n?
Gotta burn this fat! Gotta get in shape!
Oh! That's a great idea'n!
Then I'll be stronger!
Good! You can't get off the island otherwise'n!
And then... I'll be even stronger!
Yes! That sounds good too'n!
And then I'll be much, much stronger!
Oh? Th-That much'n?!
Much, much, much, much,
much, much stronger!
Wow! You're very motivated'n!
To get you up and working
out so vigorously'n...
What exactly was written in that paper'n?
I received a message from our captain.
A message?
What're you talking about? Get on already.
You're one of us now, aren't you?
Luffy!
U-Usopp?
Y-You...
were here too?
Defeat him! We're all
going back together, Luffy!
Of course we will!
I thought...
that Luffy could become King of the Pirates
all on his own while I stood by and watched.
We've finally made it this far!
We'll see this wall again when we
cross the other half of the world!
When that happens,
I'll be King of the Pirates!
But I was wrong.
He has lots of enemies stronger than him.
Even Luffy can lose!
He's pushing himself too hard!
He's crying out in agony!
That's why...
he needs to depend on my strength!
Heracles'n!
I wanna get stronger!
I wanna get much, much,
much stronger, and...!
Please... Master Heracles'n...
Huh? M-Master'n...?
I've been curious about
those weapons of yours.
Your strength is what allows you to survive
on this island. Teach me your ways!
Strength'n? I'm a strong master'n?
Yeah! My master is amazingly strong!
And, my name is...
Heracles'n!
That's such a cool name!
R-Right! Take a seat, Usopp'n.
Yes, Master!
Listen up, Usopp, my student'n!
Much of the local flora consists of pop green.
They can sprout anywhere in an instant
and have quite the mean streak!
Behold! Their seeds'n.
Pop green?
Indeed'n!
They all have their uses'n.
Is that so'n?
Wait for me, Luffy!
Run, Usopp'n! This forest
will make you stronger'n!
To help you become King of the Pirates,
I will become a true King of Snipers!
Now to Gloom Island on the Grand Line,
in the ruins of the Muggy Kingdom...
Please!
Teach me the way of your sword!
I'm disappointed in you, Roronoa.
You would beg your enemy to instruct you?
How shameless!
Leave. I have no business
with a wretch like you.
It would seem I overestimated you.
What's your game?
You're embarrassing yourself.
I want to become stronger!
Powerless against baboons
and incapable of setting sail,
you returned here, tail between your legs;
I have nothing to teach a man such as you.
I defeated the baboons.
Did he now?
All that's left is to take your head!
But I'm not so stupid to think
I can beat you right now.
Baffling... If you still see me as an enemy,
why bow down and demand tutelage?
For what purpose?!
To surpass you!
You would have me temper the very sword
whose blade would claim my head?
You are a strange one. What foolishness...
And still, you remain shameless.
It would seem... your ambition
exceeds even your pride.
You there, ghost girl... Tend to his wounds.
Hey! Don't tell me what to do!
Training commences upon your recovery.
Dammit! Every last one of you
is so demanding of me!
Come on, get back to your room!
What a clumsy fool.
When a man of his caliber sets aside his pride,
it is always for the sake of another.
It's "3D" crossed out with "2Y" written next?
You're right! It's tattooed
onto Straw Hat's right arm!
We made a promise to meet
at a certain place in three days.
So much for that plan.
So "3D" stands for "three days"?
But since the "3D" is
crossed out, the "2Y" means...
Two years.
Two years?!
We won't be meeting up in
three days, but in two years.
Everything else was to distract
from his true intentions.
This message was meant only for us.
Luffy has made his decision.
As we are, we'd be rushing headlong
into disaster in the New World.
We'll stay put, grow stronger...
and then we'll definitely set sail once more!
– See you at Sabaody Archipelago in two years!
Here he comes.
Jinbe! Thanks for everything!
I'm the one who ought to be thanking you!
You listened to my plea and
helped me escape from Impel Down,
and though I am shamed, I go on living.
My sincerest apologies!
I thought I told you to stop that.
If not for you, I probably wouldn't
have gotten to Marine Headquarters.
Raise your head.
I suppose so.
And I might have the chance
to help you again someday.
With that said, let us meet again
in two years at Fishman Island!
I look forward to the day when you
arrive together with your crew!
Sure!
– Take care!
– Farewell!
This island will do the trick.
Known as the Island of Forty-Eight Seasons,
its climate ruthlessly shifts once per week.
Luffy!
I will bring you food from the
Isle of Women each and every day!
What?! Seriously, Hancock?
Then bring more of that special dish,
the gorgon something-or-other!
It was so good!
O-Of course!
– Wow! Snake Princess!
Whatever your heart desires most,
I will bring it to you!
Also... that's officially the tenth time
you have used my name.
Th-Then... we must be engaged!
Nyo you are nyot! And why
do you keep moving backward?!
Hancock, we can't have you
pampering him like that.
While Luffy is training, all your women
will have to remain off the island.
What?!
What gives you the right
to decide such things, Rayleigh?!
Your answer will determine
whether you turn to stone!
He can find all the food he needs
in the mountains, forests, rivers, or ocean!
Please release his nyose, Snake Princess!
If he can't handle basic survival skills,
he'll never make it as a pirate!
This is all to help Luffy!
Did you say... this is to help Luffy?
I did.
If it is to help Luffy...
then I shall endure it!
But Rayleigh, this island
is extremely dangerous.
If anything happens to him–
If nothing happens to him,
it wouldn't be training.
Send prayers if you're worried.
All right. Now we are the only
two humans on this island.
Take a look at this vast wilderness.
There was once a great civilization here,
but humans eventually lost the battle for survival.
It's a harsh environment,
where only the strong can thrive.
I smell adventure!
The island is crawling with beasts.
There's no counting them all.
In your current state, I sense about
500 that you can't beat.
You'll need to become stronger
to even sleep at night.
How can you tell what's here
or how many there are?
It's not just me. You, too,
will learn to use this power.
The power known as haki!
Hey, look out! Something's coming, Rayleigh!
Gramps! Behind you! Behind you!
Listen well, Luffy. Haki is a latent
power dwelling within everyone.
An elephant?! It's five times
as big as a normal one!
That elephant is so cool!
Presence. Fighting spirit. Control.
People use it in much the same way
as their normal senses.
However, most humans don't
even realize they have this power,
or they spend their entire lives
trying in vain to develop it.
To never doubt! That is the strength you seek.
L-Look out!
Gear Second!
Jet Pistol!
Damn... What's with this elephant?
He's strong and fast!
Watch closely.
Most haki manifests within two categories.
Look out!
Relax.
The elephant will swing its trunk
at me from the right.
The power to sense your
opponent's presence...
This is observation haki.
Amazing...
Hone this ability to discern the location
and number of foes beyond your vision.
It will even let you predict
your enemy's next move.
A kick with your left foot.
Mantra.
On the sky island of Skypiea,
they call this power "mantra."
That was close!
Next up: armament haki.
Using this power is like wearing invisible armor.
Gramps!
I... I know that one!
Ashigara Dokkoi!
Of course, the stronger your armor,
the more powerful your attacks.
Hey, ow! I'm made of rubber,
but that flick really hurt!
This is the most useful part of this power.
When battling devil fruit users, armament haki
is the most effective way to oppose them.
Otherwise, you must find a weakness
in their individual powers.
Even the practically invincible logia types,
who boast freely flowing bodies,
are vulnerable when struck by it.
Was this why you could touch Kizaru?
So, if I used this, even I could fight
Marine guys like Smokey or Aokiji?
People can also imbue
their weapons with this power.
You saw the Kuja Tribe's archery?
Yeah...
Then they weren't just steel arrows...!
Observation and armament...
these are two types of haki.
However,
a select few people in the world
can utilize another kind of haki.
Pay attention.
This power controls your opponent!
Conqueror's haki.
Those who have made a name
for themselves in this world,
are often found to possess this power.
However,
while a person can come to control it,
conqueror's haki cannot be
harnessed through training.
It is the very spirit of the user.
It strengthens with individual growth.
That's what you used
back at the auction house!
I'm sure you've experienced it already.
Your potential as a conqueror
is already awakening.
But you should refrain from using it until
you've got it completely under control.
There's a potential for affecting
innocent bystanders around you.
Hm? What is it?
Amazing!
The Pirate King's crew can beat giant monsters
like these without even touching them?
Did your respect for me grow?
Yeah!
But I've seen this haki stuff lots before.
Shanks... Grandpa...
Enel and Aisa,
and then there's Hancock
and the Kuja warriors.
I'm sure you have. However, learning
to use haki is not so simple a task.
Right.
Usually, the amount of time
we have wouldn't be enough,
but you have a lot of potential.
In two years, I will teach you the basics of
observation, armament and even conqueror's haki.
Uh-huh.
You see, most people tend to specialize
in just one type over the others,
due to their skills or weaknesses.
They gravitate toward the one
they're best at and hone nothing else.
If you become skilled in all three,
you'll achieve so much more.
Sure, I got it.
Well then...
I won't go easy on you, Luffy.
Of course! I wouldn't expect you to!
Ah, hold on!
Gramps said this was the one safe spot, right?
Straw Hat Luffy is taking
a little break from pirating.
Oh, right.
This, too...
Guys...
– Luffy!
Hey, hurry!
Let's get started!
Got it!
I'm in your hands, Gramps!
That won't do.
Say, "Please teach me, Mr. Rayleigh"!
No, "Professor Rayleigh"!
Or, "Master"?
Thanks! Please teach me, Rayleigh!
Well, it doesn't matter.
Zoro, Usopp, Sanji, Nami,
Chopper, Robin, Franky, Brook...
and Ace and Sabo!
I promise once more...
I'm gonna get stronger!
The Grand Line, Near the Sabaody Archipelago
Trafalgar Law
A Winter Island, the New World
X Drake
A Spring Island, the New World
Scratchmen Apoo
San Juan Wolf
On a certain Burning Island in the New World
Marshall D. Teach
Jesus Burgess
Shiryu
Avalo Pizarro
Lafitte
Doc Q
Vasco Shot
Catarina Devon
Van Ogre
Jewelry Bonney
The Holy Land Mary Geoise
Torino Kingdom, the South Blue
The Kingdom of Armsolong
Sword Mountain Island, the Grand Line
A Colossal Bridge, the East Blue
Bowin Islands
The Grand Line
Muggy Kingdom Ruins
Kuraigana Island, Grand Line
A Few Days Earlier
In the Calm Belt
Luscaina, a Deserted Island
Northwest of the Isle of Women, Calm Belt